<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Course resources on COMP52315 – Performance Engineering, Vectorisation and GPU Programming</title><link>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/</link><description>Recent content in Course resources on COMP52315 – Performance Engineering, Vectorisation and GPU Programming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contact details</title><link>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/contact/</guid><description>Contact details # I am Massimiliano Fasi and I am teaching the course in January 2023. You can contact me by sending an email to massimiliano.fasi@durham.ac.uk.
This website and all course materials are hosted on GitHub. If you have a suggestion or want to report a mistake, please use the GitHub issue tracker. Pull requests are also welcome.</description></item><item><title>Hamilton accounts</title><link>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/hamilton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/hamilton/</guid><description>Access to Hamilton # For many of the exercises in the course, we will be using the Hamilton supercomputer. If you do not have an account on the machine, please apply for one by completing the registration form on the Self Service Portal. More information on access requests is available here.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be logging in a lot—please follow the tips on how to configure ssh for swifter login.
Hamilton quick start guide # This quick start guide is intended to get you up and running on the Hamilton 8 supercomputer, but it should not be considered a replacement for the official documentation—please refer to it for anything that you cannot find here.</description></item><item><title>ssh configuration</title><link>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/configuration/</guid><description>ssh tips &amp;amp; tricks # Setting up simpler logins # It can be tedious to remember to type long login commands every time when logging in via ssh to Hamilton. I therefore recommend that you set up an ssh config file.
Additionally, you might also want to set up ssh keys for passwordless login.
The ssh-config configuration file # GNU/Linux and MacOS When you run it, ssh reads a configuration file at $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Unix resources</title><link>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/unix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scicomp-durham.github.io/COMP52315/setup/unix/</guid><description>Using Unix-like systems for computational science # This course presupposes some level of familiarity with commandline interfaces. You have encountered these already in the previous term. In case you need a quick refresher, I recommend the material produced by the Software Carpentry project.
They have a number of useful lessons and materials providing introductory training on how to do things like use the Unix shell, version control with git, and some introductory programming and plotting in Python.</description></item></channel></rss>